### ARMANDO GONZALEZ

Atlanta, GA • U.S. Citizen armandogonz14@gatech.edu

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Armando Gonzalez is a passionate, personable team player, with two years of experience in software development and an intense interest for developing and designing products centered on an engaging and empowering user experience. In his free time, he enjoys free writing and making art of many forms – from pixel drawings to small video games.

# **EDUCATION**

# GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, College of Computing

Atlanta, Georgia

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** 

May 2020

Concentration in Media and People

#### **SKILLS**

Technical: Proficiency in Java, Golang, Python, Elasticsearch, PHP, AWS;

Familiarity with C, Android Development, AngularJS, Sql, Shell Scripting

Proficiency in Object Oriented Programming, Restful Web Services, Service Development; **Application:** 

Familiarity with Aspect Oriented Programming, Application Development, Game Development

Technical Project Management, Organization and Leadership of Groups, Planning and Running Events, Leadership:

Organization and Leadership of Groups

Public Speaking (Presentational, Interpersonal, and Written), Group Mediation, and Problem Solving **Communication:** 

#### **PROJECTS**

#### GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

#### **Gameboy Advance Game Development**

Spring 2018

- Created a game for the Gameboy Advance called Bit-a-Fish
- Wrote the entirety of the game code in C
- Created original art for the game's sprites

# **Android Application Development**

Spring 2017

- Developed an application in class that allows users to submit and view water reports in the area
- Application backed by a live database and uses a live updated Google map

# VIP Research Program

Fall 2016 - Spring 2018

- Developed a database-backed, live map with JS utilized by managers of Georgia Tech's bus system
- Collected data on bus system behavior using an Android application and Estimote beacons

### MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL, ADVANCED MEDIA

Wrote a shell script to check the health of various app deployments in real time	Summer 2016
Implemented a powerful, free-form, and text-based search engine for a web-based application	Summer 2016
Performed an extensive backfill of media data using Amazon Web Services (AWS)	Summer 2017

# **PATIETNCO**

Rebuilt a search engine to improve its speed, accuracy, and flexibility when searching patient data	Fall 2017
Wrote an internal tool/service that used OCR to read images and searched for associated information	Summer 2018
Contributed to a new-new project that reconciled funds and medical expenses across distributed systems	Spring 2019

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### DISNEY STREAMING SERVICES

New York, New York Starting Summer 2019

Incoming Software Engineering Intern, Multimedia Engineering Tools and Services Term

#### **PATIENTCO** Atlanta, Georgia Spring 2019

# Software Engineering Coop, FinTech Team

- Individually contributed to regular, full-time development work as a full-stack engineer
- Produced production level software on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Kanban)
- Formally recruited during career fairs and by delivering a Tech Talk on Georgia Tech's campus

- Participated in on-call rotations to get more exposure to full-time work
- Contributed to several operations and systems that were integral to the business and on strict deadlines

# **Software Engineering Coop, Coop Team**

Summer 2018

- Performed as team lead on another net-new service with cross-departmental stakeholders
- Managed an internal project using Agile Software (Kanban) Methods and taught these methods to others
- Delivered several formal demos and presentation to other members of the Engineering Department, and Customer Support
- Discovered a major security and compliance vulnerability in one of our vendors' websites

#### **Software Engineering Coop, Platform Team**

Fall 2017

- Individually developed a net-new service and designed a search cluster using Elasticsearch and Golang
- Developed production level software on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Kanban)
- Participated in a career fair and other follow-up recruiting efforts on behalf of the company
- Delivered a formal demo and presentations to other members of the Engineering Department and C.S.O.

BAMTECH LLC New York, New York

# Software Engineering Intern, Multimedia Engineering Team

Summer 2017

- Worked as an independent, full-stack engineer in a fast-paced environment
- Developed production level software on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Scrum)
- Participated in a department-wide Hackathon that exposed me to other teams within Engineering

#### MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL, ADVANCED MEDIA

New York, New York

Summer 2016

- Software Engineering Intern, Multimedia Development Team
  Shortly graduated from small projects to full-stack applications
- Actively participated on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Scrum)
- Projects required exposure to all major touch points of MLBAM's technical ecosystem
- Delivered several formal demos and presentations to other interns and members of the Engineering Department

#### **LEADERSHIP**

# GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Atlanta, Georgia

Georgia Tech Spirit Program, College Mascot

Fall 2017 - Spring 2019

- Represented Georgia Tech on local, state, and national level as an ambassador and symbol for Georgia Tech
- Maintained strict fitness and diet regimen, training daily while balancing school and extracurricular activities
- Committed an average of 10 hours per week towards attending on and off campus events with high energy and enthusiasm

# New Student and Sophomore Programs, Wreck Camp Director of Staff Development

Fall 2017 – Fall 2018

- Led a staff of 40 through weekly trainings focused on group mediation and leadership
- Attended the Southern Regional Orientation Workshop to learn more about leadership and group management
- Helped plan a three-day, extended orientation camp to help transition incoming Georgia Tech students

# New Student and Sophomore Programs, Wreck Camp Counselor

Spring 2016 - Fall 2017

- Co-led a small group of students as a part of an extended orientation program
- Joined a staff of 30+ students focused on community building and transitioning into life at Georgia Tech